Guide to the Judy Blume Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2017 Acquisition, 1952-2017; 117.75; (125 boxes) + 1 roll
  - Glenn Horowitz Bookseller Office Material, 1956-2001; 11.5; (11 boxes)
    The Glenn Horowitz Bookseller Office Material consists chiefly of correspondence dating from the late 1990s and early 2000s and writings. Drafts and proofs can be found for many books by Blume, and in some cases multiple drafts can be found for individual tiles, including: Just as long as we're together (1987), Smart women (1983), Here's to you, Rachel Robinson (1993), and Fudge-a-mania (1990).
    - Just as long as we're together, notes and drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, second draft, undated (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, draft C, undated (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, draft D, undated; 2 folders (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, first draft, undated; 2 folders (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, revised drafts, undated; 8 folders (Box 107)
    - Just as long as we're together, revised drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Smart women, first draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Smart women, second draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Smart women, third draft, undated; 6 folders (Box 108)
    - Smart women, revised drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Smart women, notes, 1981-1983, undated (Box 108)
    - Smart women, first draft, undated; 2 folders (Box 109)
    - Smart women, fourth draft, undated (Box 109)
    - Smart women, fifth draft, undated; 5 folders (Box 109)
    - Smart women, "incomplete", undated; 7 folders (Box 109)
    - Smart women, drafts, undated; 5 folders (Box 110)
    - Are you there God? It's me, Margaret, notes, undated (Box 110)
    - Are you there God? It's me, Margaret, draft, undated (Box 110)
    - It's not the end of the world, drafts, 1971, undated; 5 folders (Box 110)
    - It's not the end of the world, notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Otherwise known as Sheila the great, draft, undated (Box 110)
    - Otherwise known as Sheila the great, second draft, 1971–1972; 3 folders (Box 110)
    - Otherwise known as Sheila the great, notes, undated (Box 110)
    - Deenie, drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 111)
    - Deenie, notes, undated (Box 111)
    - Starring Sally J. Freedman as herself, drafts, 1975, undated; 4 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, first draft, 1992; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, "second full draft", 1992; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, third draft, 1992; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, fourth draft, 1992 December; 3 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, fifth draft, 1992 December 18 (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, December 19, 1992 draft, 1992-1993, undated; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, January 1993 drafts, 1993 January; 3 folders (Box 112)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, drafts, 1993, undated; 8 folders (Box 112)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, notes, undated (Box 112)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, correspondence, 1993, undated (Box 112)
    - Here's to you, Rachel Robinson, research materials, 1993, undated (Box 112)
    - Fudge-a-mania, "second draft Jan, 1990", 1987–1990 (Box 112)
    - Fudge-a-mania, "Fudgie/'89", 1989 (Box 112)
    - Fudge-a-mania, drafts, 1989, undated; 5 folders (Box 112)
    - Fudge-a-mania, drafts, 1989-1990, undated; 17 folders (Box 113)
    - Fudge-a-mania, "dummy, (advanced reading copy with corrections)", 1990 (Box 114)
    - Fudge-mania, correspondence, 1990, undated (Box 114)
    - Fudge-a-mania, page proofs, 1990, undated; 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Superfudge, galley proof, undated (Box 114)
    - Superfudge, drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 114)
    - Letters to Judy, proofs, undated (Box 114)
    - Letters to Judy, galley, 1985, undated; 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Letters to Judy, drafts, undated (Box 114)
    - Tiger eyes, drafts, undated; 6 folders (Box 115)
    - Description of correspondents, undated (Box 115)
    - "Judy Blume correspondence", 1969-1992, undated (Box 115)
    - Battin High School Year Book, 1956 (Box 115)
    - "Special fan 2000", 1999-2000, undated (Box 115)
    - "2000 correspondence personal", 1998-2000, undated (Box 115)
    - "Professional correspondence 2000", 1999-2000, undated (Box 115)
    - "Read in 2000" (Box 115)
    - "Personal correspondence 2001", 1997-2001, undated (Box 115)
    - "Professional correspondence 2001", 2000-2001, undated (Box 115)
    - "Digital heroes", 2000-2001, undated (Box 116)
    - "Corres: special fan 1999 (includes e-mail)", 1998-1999, undated (Box 116)
    - "Corres: personal 1999", 1997-2000, undated (Box 116)
    - "Corres: professional 1999", 1998–1999 (Box 116)
    - "Fans - special letters 1998-99", 1999, undated (Box 116)
    - "Read in pre-2000", 1999 (Box 116)
    - "Corres: professional 1999 (cont.)", 1998-1999, undated (Box 116)
    - "Correspondence - 99 professional", 1998-1999, undated (Box 116)
    - "Manuscripts (unpublished)", undated (Box 116)
    - "Manuscripts (unpublished) Donna + Jessie", undated (Box 116)
    - "The Girl who was a dog", undated (Box 116)
    - "The very first of "Fudge" Fudge's birth, late 60's?", undated (Box 116)
    - "You mom, you?", 1967 (Box 116)
    - "You mom, you?", 1967 (Box 117)
    - "The Time of the treasure!", 1967 (Box 117)
    - "Early writings 'Flying munchgins' (1st pub. story) 'How I get my jollies,' others late 60's?, undated (Box 116)
    - "Socko-bocko", 1967 (Box 117)
    - "The Green star is not so far", 1967 (Box 117)
    - "The Little hairy fellows", 1967 (Box 117)
  - October 2017 Addition, 1961-2017; 6.63; (8 boxes) + 1 roll
    Box 119 (born digital): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    The October 2017 Addition contains correspondence, clippings, research files, material relating to public engagements and events, such as interviews, speeches, and book and promotional tours, and other papers.
    - "Model letters samples", 1986-2013, undated (Box 118)
    - "Model letters + email", 1991-1997, undated (Box 118)
    - "Judy's cover letters sent with her quilts", 1984, undated (Box 118)
    - "Special correspondence", 2000-2012, undated (Box 118)
    - "Mostly fan mail", 1999 (Box 118)
    - "Completed emails with Judy's notes", 2006–2011 (Box 118)
    - "Special letters/emails", 2000-2003, undated (Box 118)
    - "Special" fan mail, 2009-2013, undated; 5 folders (Box 118)
    - " Summer sisters negative", 1999, undated (Box 118)
    - "Fan mail", 1986-2016, undated (Box 118)
    - "Dr. Seuss - tribute by Judy 1991" (Box 118)
    - " Forever info possibly dupes?", 1989-2005, undated (Box 118)
    - " Forever package", 1999-2005, undated (Box 118)
    - "Many responses from Judy to fan letters…", 1991-2005, undated (Box 118)
    - "Fan mail - censorship positive", 1995–2000 (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1998, undated (Box 118)
    - "Censorship", 1988-2015, undated (Box 118)
    - "Censorship 'packet' Forever ", 1988-1990, undated (Box 118)
    - "Censorship 'packet' Blubber ", 1989-1999, undated (Box 118)
    - "Corres: special fan 1999 censorship", 1999-2001, undated (Box 118)
    - Summer sisters, "web info + more", undated (Box 118)
    - "Sample pages - quilts, advice - bio", undated (Box 118)
    - "JB/for speech mat. on censorship", 1998-2003, undated (Box 118)
    - "American Academy of Arts & Letters - May 2017" (Box 118)
    - Deenie material, 1999-2003, undated (Box 118)
    - "NY Times Op-ed 10/29/99 'Is Harry Potter evil?'", 1999 (Box 118)
    - "Correspondence", 1985-2014, undated (Box 118)
    - "Don't make me laugh MS PG w/edits", 1999 (Box 118)
    - "Original manuscript", undated (Box 118)
    - Tales of a fourth grade nothing, "40th anniv. media campaign 4/2012", 2011-2012, undated (Box 118)
    - "Sex education", 2001, undated (Box 118)
    - "Rejections", 1968–1970 (Box 118)
    - Book covers, undated (Box 118)
    - In the unlikely event, correspondence, 2014-2017, undated; 3 folders (Box 118)
    - Electronic media, undated; 1 (Box 119)
      Box 119 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Box list, undated (Box 120)
    - "Censorship articles", 1999 (Box 120)
    - "E-Toys interview 11/99", 1999 November (Box 120)
    - "Statements and articles from/by JB", 1986-1987, undated (Box 120)
    - "Fan letters - Jane Startz package", 1998-1999, undated (Box 120)
    - "Planned Prnthd hate mail 2009" (Box 120)
    - "Censorship letters - general old", 1993-1999, undated (Box 120)
    - "Fan mail - weird", 2000-2007, undated (Box 120)
    - "The proposal to involve JB + LB in a film production", undated (Box 120)
    - "Film people", 2005–2006 (Box 120)
    - "Muse Production", 2003, undated (Box 120)
    - "Norma Klein - tribute 2014", 2014, undated (Box 120)
    - Forever, "UK interviews - 30th anniversary", 2005, undated (Box 120)
    - "Miscellaneous interviews", 2007-2015, undated (Box 120)
    - "Glamour", 2004–2005 (Box 120)
    - "Child", 2004, undated (Box 120)
    - "National Book", 2004, undated (Box 120)
    - Miscellaneous material, undated (Box 120)
    - "Author Zone Magazine interview 2000" (Box 120)
    - "Some good interviews", 1993-2002, undated (Box 120)
    - Professional correspondence, 2003-2013, undated; 5 folders (Box 120)
    - "Random Buzzers April/May 2009" (Box 120)
    - "JB writes a letter re LA Public Library", 2015, undated (Box 120)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 120)
    - "Judy's original artwork & copy", undated (Box 120)
    - "Articles, including New Yorker 1983 and Yale's Mark Oppenheimer 1997 NYT Book Review", 1994-2012, undated (Box 120)
    - "Authors Guild", 1993-2002, undated (Box 120)
    - "Authors Guild Panel April 11, 1995 never given from here to there", undated (Box 120)
    - "Authors Guild Committe[e] for Free Expression", 1994-1995, undated (Box 120)
    - "My talk given at Authors Guild Benefit 1997 as Jack Kerouac (fictional teen)", 1997-2003, undated (Box 120)
    - "Bios", 2001, undated (Box 120)
    - Photographs, 1976-2001, undated; 18 folders (Box 120)
    - Promotional material, undated (Box 121)
    - NYU notebook, 2017, undated (Box 121)
    - Box list, undated (Box 121)
    - Long Lots Elementary School Westport, CT, 2004, undated (Box 121)
    - "Univ. of Wisconsin Charlotte Zolotow Lecture", 2008, undated (Box 121)
    - "Fall events 2009", 2007-2015, undated (Box 121)
    - "What do kids like to read? The Cost of fear", undated (Box 121)
    - "Writer's group talk", undated (Box 121)
    - "University of S. Mississippi 2009", 2008-2009, undated (Box 121)
    - "USM", 2008-2009, undated (Box 121)
    - "University of Southern Mississippi Medallion 2009", 2009, undated (Box 121)
    - "That kid is just like me! Finding friends in books", undated (Box 121)
    - "Tropic cinema 2004", undated (Box 121)
    - "Take stock in children commencement 5/19/07", 2007 May (Box 121)
    - "Speech materials", 2004-2007, undated; 2 folders (Box 121)
    - "Slide show", 1995, undated (Box 121)
    - "SCBWI", undated (Box 121)
    - "Reach out and read", undated (Box 121)
    - "Special fan individuals Ellen Bright", 2001-2002, undated (Box 121)
    - "Jason's correspondence", 1998-1999, undated (Box 121)
    - "Special" fan mail, 1998-2002, undated (Box 121)
    - "Special" fan mail, 2000-2008, undated; 10 folders (Box 122)
    - Box list, undated (Box 122)
    - "Judy's idea box", undated (Box 122)
    - "Sample responses", 1982-1986, undated (Box 122)
    - ACLU garden party speech notes, 2008 (Box 122)
    - "Speeches/appearances", undated (Box 122)
    - "NCTE & ALAN awards November 2013", 2013, undated (Box 122)
    - "Mt. Holyoke - May, 2013", 2003, undated (Box 122)
    - "Friends KW Library", 2016 January 25 (Box 122)
    - "Correspondence: SCBW A95.0", 1993-1996, undated (Box 122)
    - "SCBW Awards", 1993-2003, undated (Box 122)
    - "SCBWI miscellaneous", 1997, undated (Box 122)
    - "Santa who", 2006, undated (Box 122)
    - "National Book Festival 2009", 2009, undated; 2 folders (Box 122)
    - "National Book Fndt - 2004", undated (Box 122)
    - "Various invitations from schools", 1998 (Box 122)
    - " Wifey the Movie Monarch Productions", 2003 March 25 (Box 122)
    - "NYU: transcript - 1961" (Box 122)
    - "New York University plaque", 1993 (Box 122)
    - "For Yale (Judy's thanks to writers for NCAC contributions)", 1999 December 9 (Box 122)
    - "For Yale re: NYS regents exam", 2002 (Box 122)
    - "Censorship", undated (Box 122)
    - "Special correspondence from authors to Judy", 1995-2010, undated (Box 122)
    - "Bullying", undated (Box 122)
    - "Stuff", 2009 (Box 122)
    - "NCTE Seattle '91", undated (Box 122)
    - "NYU commencement 2007" (Box 122)
    - "Speeches - Pen/Faulkner Fall 1999", undated (Box 122)
    - "McGovern Award 11/28/11 Smithsonian Association", 2011–2012 (Box 122)
    - "NYCLU '08", undated (Box 122)
    - "Commencement address", 2001, undated (Box 123)
    - "On writing", undated (Box 123)
    - "Commencement", undated (Box 123)
    - National Coalition Against Censorship 35 years, 2009 October 19 (Box 123)
    - Box list, undated (Box 123)
    - "Miscellaneous speeches", 1981-2008, undated; 4 folders (Box 123)
    - "Political", 2008, undated (Box 123)
    - "Regina Award CLA - April 8, 205 Orlando, FL", 2015 (Box 123)
    - "ALA Forever Award", 1996, undated (Box 123)
    - "ALA speech - July, 1996 Margaret E. Edwards Award", 1996, undated (Box 123)
    - "ABA 1988 - Ten yrs. in ten min." (Box 123)
    - "ACLU KW 2014", 2014, undated (Box 123)
    - "ALA Chicago Judith King July 10th-13th 2009", 2008-2009, undated (Box 123)
    - "Brooklyn Public Library", 2000, undated (Box 123)
    - "Chicago Tribune YA Book Prize 6/2013 Printers Row Lit Fest" (Box 123)
    - "Creative Coalition '97 1st Amendment", 1997 November (Box 123)
    - "BEA Book Expo 5/08", undated (Box 123)
    - "Day of Caring - Miami, May 11, 2013", 2013 undated; 2 folders (Box 123)
    - Deenie, 2003, undated (Box 123)
    - "Joyce Meskis - Author's Guild", undated (Box 123)
    - " Forever & fondue story", 1991-1993, undated (Box 123)
    - In the unlikely event, "book tour 2015", undated (Box 124)
    - In the unlikely event, "book tour - US/UK/Canada", 2015, undated (Box 124)
    - In the unlikely event, "paperback May 2016", 2016, undated (Box 124)
    - In the unlikely event, "reviews", 2015, undated (Box 124)
    - In the unlikely event, "book tour 2015", 2015, undated (Box 124)
    - In the unlikely event, "Vintage 5/2016 paperback release", 2016, undated (Box 124)
    - "KWL literary seminar", undated (Box 124)
    - "KWLS 2005 humor", 2005, undated (Box 124)
    - Box list, undated (Box 124)
    - "Censorship - Mark Twain", 2011, undated (Box 124)
    - "TV Guide article Sesame/Clinton", 1993 (Box 124)
    - "Censorship articles/materials 1986-", 1990-2005, undated (Box 124)
    - "VT banned books info", 2003, undated (Box 124)
    - "Censorship", 2009, undated (Box 124)
    - "Speech material on censorship", 1990-1991, undated (Box 124)
    - "Censorship speech materials", 2002, undated (Box 124)
    - "Clippings/articles 2013", 2013, undated; 2 folders (Box 124)
    - "Clippings/press pre 2012", 1999-2013, undated; 3 folders (Box 124)
    - "Clippings - press 2014", 2014, undated; 2 folders (Box 124)
    - "Press/clippings 2015", 2015, undated; 3 folders (Box 125)
    - "Press clips 2016", 2016, undated (Box 125)
    - "Censorship materials - 1993", 1990-2002, undated (Box 125)
    - "For JB's speech - May, 1993", 1989-1992, undated (Box 125)
    - Poster, undated (Box 126 (Roll))
- September 2018 Acquisition, 1977-2018, undated; 3.09; (3 boxes)
  - "Agents - British, David Higham Associates, Jacqueline Korn", 1996-1997 (Box 127)
  - "American Academy of Arts & Letters, May 17, 2017" (Box 127)
  - "C is for caregiver," illustration by Laura Crawford, undated (Box 126 (Roll))
  - "Corres: Agents various (the search) 1997", 1994-1997 (Box 127)
  - "Correspondence: open agent: Herta Ryder, British", 1990-1996 (Box 127)
  - In the unlikely event, publicity schedule, 2016- (Box 127)
  - Letter removed from Funny business by Leonard S. Marcus (2009), 2010 February 12 (Box 127)
  - Letter removed from With strength and splendor by Lisa V. Kogen (2008), 2009 January 6 (Box 127)
  - Memory games by Laura Crawford, undated (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2018, undated (Box 127)
  - Photographs of 2017 award winners, American Academy of Arts & Letters (Box 126 (Roll))
  - Posters of Judy Blume, "NJ Library Champion", undated (Box 126 (Roll))
  - Printed material, 2004, 2018; 4 (Box 127)
  - "Starring Judy M. Sussman as herself," by the Hebrew Academy fifth and sixth grade girls, 1977, undated (Box 128)
  - Sweater knitted by Essie Sussman for jacket photo for Smart women, undated (Box 129)
  - Sweater knitted by Essie Sussman for jacket photo for Wifey, undated (Box 129)